The "rose" is the center dot on any face that has one (i.e., 1, 3, and the "petals" are all dots around it – the 1 face has no petals, the 3 face has two petals and the 5 face has four petals. The dice faces without center dots (i.e., 2, 4, and 6) do not count. Counting the total petal dots yields that round's answer.

Equivalently, one may sum the faces of odd dice, and then subtract the number of them. Thus, in a roll of 2, 3, 4, 5, and 3, the odd faces sum to 11. There are three odd dice, so the solution is 11 − 3, or 8.